本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
翻译：小松狮   贝贝船长   silmar   marvin      校对：小路
特效：Will     时间轴：虫不知      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
你
You are..
有货吗
You selling?
我不懂你什么意思
I don't know what you're talking about.
好  那就算了
OK. That's cool.
我的意思是  如果你有货
I'm just saying, you know, if you were selling,
我想来点儿试试
I could maybe do with a teenth.
你在开玩笑吧
You're kidding, right?
伙计  我已经闻到条子的味道了
Dude, I so smell bacon.
什么  你在说什么
What? What are you talking about?
我不知道为什么
Gee, I don't know.
那边  那辆棕色货车
How about over there. That brown van.
-那是你的  对吧  -什么棕色货车
- That's yours, right? - What brown van?
停得那么隐蔽
Parked all inconspicuous.
肯定是警车
It's a cop van.
那里居然还有一辆
Another one right over there.
"杜克城市鲜花店"  别装了
"Duke city flowers"? Come on!
就不能有点创意吗
Can't you at least be original?
伙计  我真的只想买点货
Dude, I just want to get high.
一辆鲜花货车
A flower van.
知道吗  你们应该开辆垃圾车
You know what you should do is a garbage truck.
说真的  不是想要冒犯你
Seriously. And I don't mean to disrespect.
但是如果你真的藏了一堆条子
But if you put a bunch of cops
在垃圾车后面
In the back of a garbage truck
我就不可能真的以为
There's no way I'm seriously thinking
垃圾车后面会有条子跳出来
That there's cops in the back of a garbage truck.
只是建议  唷  你们可以考虑一下
It's a freebie, yo. Just think about it.
考虑一下  孩子们
Think about it, boys!
好吧  我找错人了
All right. I'm hitting it.
你们这些人会这么容易放弃吗
You dudes give up that easy?
我不是条子
I'm not a cop.
那就把衣服撩起来
Then lift your shirt.
让我看看有没有带窃听器
Show me you're not wearing a wire.
好吧  知道吗
All right, you know what?
为了证明你就是个混蛋
Just to show you you're being an asshole.
我被白光刺得睁不开眼了
I'm blinded by white.
王八蛋
Douchebag.
别这样  只是开玩笑  回来吧
Come on. I was joking. Come on.
别生气  坐下  来吧
Don't walk away angry. Sit down. Come on.
你在抱怨什么
I mean, what are you complaing about?
你还算有点腹肌
You got abs, man. Kinda.
随你怎么说
Whatever, dude.
我不太想买了
I'm not even sure I want to buy anymore.
你已经把我的瘾都搞没了
I think you turned me off to the whole thing.
伙计  别这样
Come on. Don't be like that.
我只是要先证明
I just need you to prove it, you know?
证明你不是条子
Prove you're not a cop.
要怎么做你才相信
How the hell am I supposed to do that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
有了
I got it.
到那里  给那家伙脸上来一拳
Go over there and punch that dude right in the face.
哪个
Which dude?
那个吗
That dude?
没门  他会把我揍扁的
No way. He'd kick my ass.
那倒是真的
True that.
太难了
This is so hard, you know?
我知道了
I know.
很容易
It's simple.
如果你问一个条子他是不是条子
If you ask a cop if he's a cop,
他有责任告知你身份
He's, like, obligated to tell you.
宪法里那么规定的
It's in the constitution.
美国宪法吗
Constitution of America?
来吧  你问吧
So go ahead and ask.
你是条子吗
Are you a cop?
不是这样的  应该正式一定
Not like that. ask it, like, official.
你是一位警官吗
Are you a police officer?
不 我不是一位警官
No.I am not a police officer.
那好吧  一口175
Okay, then. 175 for a teenth.
谢绝还价  唷
The price is the price, yo.
好吧
All right.
给  好好享受
There you go. Enjoy.
谢了  伙计
Thanks, man.
阿尔伯克基警察  你已经被捕  趴到地上
Albuquerque police! You're under arrest! Get on the ground!
立刻趴下
Get on your stomach now!
趴到地上
On your stomach, get on the ground!
不许动
Hold it, don't move!
待好别动
Stay down!
绝
命
毒
师
第二季
第八集
我原本有份好工作
I had a good job
直到老板指控我偷东西开始
until my boss accused me of stealing.
快打电话给索尔
I'd better call Saul!
我刚从聚会回来  担心生意的事
I was out partying, minding my own business...
你被捕了
You are under arrest.
快打电话给索尔
I'd better call Saul!
我是索尔·古德曼  你知道自己拥有的权利吗
Hi. I'm Saul Goodman. Did you know that you have rights?
宪法规定你有  我也说你有
The constitution says you do. And so do I.
除非你被定罪  在此之前我都相信
I believe that until proven guilty,
这个国家的男女老少都是清白的
Every man, woman, and child in this country is innocent.
这就是我为你而战的原因  阿尔布开克
And that's why I fight for you, Albuquerque!
快打电话给索尔
Better call Saul.
索尔·古德曼  律师
Saul Goodman, attorney at law.
我真的该买点家具了
I really need to get some furniture.
建议你从床开始
I suggest you start with a bed.
天啊  真想在这里抽一口
God, I wish we could smoke in here.
-你不能  -我知道  我知道
- Well, you can't. - I know. I know.
只是说说
I'm just saying.
别以为我闻不出这里有大麻的味道
Don't think I can't smell that weed.
你最好祈祷味道快点散掉
You better seriously hope that airs out.
我爸会扣你的押金的
My dad will keep your security deposit.
他的鼻子就像寻血猎犬一样灵敏
He has a nose like a damn bloodhound.
是吗
Yeah?
你被他抓住过吗
Has he ever caught you?
有啊
Yeah！
很多次
Many times.
听着
Well, listen.
既然我已经损失了所有的押金
Since I already lost my deposit and all,
或许我们该点上一口
Maybe we should light up.
不了  谢谢
No, thanks.
你肯定吗
You sure?
我抽一口行吗
Well, is it cool if I burn one?
你可能会改变主意
Maybe you'll change your mind.
随便你吧
Do what you want to do, I guess.
-是我说了什么吗  -没有
- What'd I say? - Nothing.
只是我得走了
I just have to go is all.
这是什么
What's this?
18个月的纪念章
My 18-month chip.
我正在戒毒
I'm in recovery. And you know,
大麻就好像是
Pot is, like,
踏脚石
Stepping stones.
戒毒
Recovery?
真厉害
That's cool.
绝对正确的选择
Right on.
很佩服
I respect that.
我也抽得不多
You know, I don't really burn much anymore.
只是有时来一根
It's just a sometime thing.
不过以后  再不会在这房子里了
But no more, like, in the house.
想出去吃点东西吗
So, you want to go grab some dinner?
我们可以去吃点中餐
I could really go for some chinese.
我真的要走了
I better hit it.
我们还好吧
We cool?
顺便说一句  你的卫星电视还开着
Your satellite's on, by the way.
屏幕看起来还真爽
That screen's bad-ass.
我只是觉得这有点过了
I just think it's asking a lot.
他知道情况
He knows it.
他只想表达歉意
He's done nothing but apologize.
以后每个周末都要去吗
Is this going to be every weekend now?
只到这个季度末  你知道的
It's just the end of the quarter. You remember how that was.
我赚的可是双倍薪酬
But I am earning double time.
看在钱的份上
There's a bright side.
等世上最懒的孩子醒了以后
So, when the laziest boy in the world wakes up,
让他把运动鞋洗了  代我跟他说再见
Tell him he better wash those sneakers. And I said "bye."
顺便告诉他这次要把鞋晾干
And tell him to let them air dry this time.
我可不喜欢鞋子在我的烘干机里
I don't want them banging the hell out of my dryer.
怎么了
What?
星期六也要穿得那么正式吗
What, you don't even get casual Saturday?
你看起来真美
You look nice is all.
这是工作  大家都这么穿
It's work. Everybody's gonna be there.
好吧
OK
今晚买个披萨吃怎么样
Maybe we'll order a pizza tonight?
再见-再见
Bye-Bye
你好  这里是沃尔特  斯凯勒和小沃特的家
Hi. You've reached Walt, Skyler, and Walter Junior.
有事请留言  我们会与你联系
Please leave a message, and we'll get back to you.
斯凯勒  你在吗
Skyler? Are you there?
我真不知道该怎么办
I just don't know what to do.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
玛丽
Hi, Mary.
是我  发生什么事了
It's me. What's up?
昨天我回家的时候  发现他回来了
Yesterday I got home and found him.
他都没告诉过我要回来
He didn't even tell me he was coming.
有人被杀了吗
A man was killed?
一个联邦调查局的  就在他眼前
A federale, right in front of him.
三个探员受了伤  有一个没了一条腿
Three agents wounded, one lost his leg.
就好像是在伊拉克一样
It's like what you hear about in Iraq or something.
-那些爆炸装置  -上帝啊
- The IEDs. - Oh, jesus.
我从史蒂芬·戈麦斯那里听来的
I had to hear about it from Steve Gomez.
汉克跟他的上级汇报了整整半小时
Hank talked to his ASAC for about an hour.
汉克都该拿奥斯卡了  他装得若无其事
Hank should win an oscar. He's so damn breezy with the man.
一挂上电话  又躺到床上去了
He hangs up the phone, goes right back to bed.
只是不停地说
And all he keeps saying is,
我很好  我没事  让我一个人呆会儿
"I'm fine. I'm fine. Leave me alone."
宝贝  现在不是时候
Baby, not now.
是我  汉克
It's me, Hank.
抱歉
Sorry.
嘿  伙计
Hey, buddy.
怎么了
What's up?
我只是
I just...
介意我进来吗
Do you mind if I...
那么
So...
你感觉怎么样
How you doing?
不太好
You know. Lousy.
拉肚子  一次又一次
Montezuma's revenge, big time.
所有的东西从我体内通过
I mean, everything's going through me
感觉就像屎通过了锡管[指拉得身体没知觉]
Like crap through a tin horn.
最好别靠我太近
Better not get too close.
我要冒个险
I'll take my chances.
你大概知道华雷斯的事了吧
I guess you heard about what happened down in Juarez?
太可怕了
Terrible.
还能指望畜生干出些什么
What do you expect? Freaking animals.
像是现代版的电影"启示录"
Like Apocalypse now down there.
[译注: 影片《现代启示录》]
就像是窝在丛林里的科茨上校
It's like colonel kurtz holed up in his jungle.
而埃尔帕索的指挥官让我回家
And my SAC in El Paso sends me home.
这可是个英明的领导决策
Now, that's a sound leadership decision right there, huh?
不让二把手
You don't put your second most senior man
继续追踪那些没娘养的混蛋
on the trail of those motherless bastards,
而是让他回家
You send him home.
我被告知  "他去取证物袋了"
I was, you know, "He's out getting an evidence bag,
"所以毫发无伤"
"and so ends up without a scratch on him.
"照片肯定是有问题"
"So must be something wrong with that picture."
所以你回来了不再回去了
So are you home for good?
随机应变吧
Playing it by ear.
"待定"
"To be determined."
有没有想过跟谁谈谈这事
Think you might want to talk it through with somebody?
跟谁  心理医生
What? A shrink?
我不能  走出这一步
I can't. Start going down that road,
工作就想别要了
Kiss your career goodbye.
或者玛丽
Or Marie.
或者我
Or me,
如果你愿意
If you like.
我不知道该怎么说
You know, I don't know how to say this.
我做的事情
You know, the things I deal with,
你我之间不太有
You and me don't have much of a...
用你的话说就是共同感受
What you might call an experiential overlap.
如果我说有呢
What if I told you we do?
我一辈子都过得战战兢兢
I have spent my whole life scared.
担心有些事会发生
Frightened of things that could happen,
可能会发生  可能不会发生
Might happen, might not happen.
整整50年我都这么过来
50 years I spent like that.
每天3点钟就惊醒
Finding myself awake at 3 in the morning.
可你知道吗
But you know what?
自从收到诊断书
Ever since my diagnosis...
我反而睡得香
I sleep just fine.
然后我意识到
And I came to realize
恐惧才是最糟糕的事情
It's that fear that's the worst of it.
恐惧才是真正的敌人
That's the real enemy.
所以
So...
回到现实世界
Get out in the real world.
狠狠地揍那个杂种
And you kick that bastard as hard as you can
打他个满地找牙
Right in the teeth.
再数一遍
Do it again.
快点
Go on.
一万整  跟上次一样  一分不少
$10,000 even. Same as last time. It's totally accurate.
我和你  会把这机器填满
You and I, we are gonna feed this machine.
让它24小时转个不停
I want it running 24 hours a day.
说的是
Right on.
不是你的吧  我可收下了
Not yours, I take it.
我们分分  一万
We got 10,
两万
20,
三万
30,
每人四万五
44.5 each.
三磅应该是每人四万八
3 pounds should be 48 each.
少了谁的
Who's short?
别急  没人少给钱
Don't freak. We didn't get ripped off.
猴子的钱还没交齐
Badger hasn't kicked in his full amount.
我听说他准备熬通宵
I know he's planning on pulling an all-nighter,
-这会儿八成还睡着呢  -那就叫他起来
- So he's probably still in the sack. - Then wake him up.
叫他给了钱再去睡
He can sleep after we're paid.
你搞这么猴急干啥
Why you gotta be such a hard on?
你不是他兄弟  你是他老板
You're not his pal. You're his boss.
得让他们怕你  才能赚大钱  记得吗
This only works when they're scared of you. Remember?
见鬼
Jack off.
直接连到语音信箱了
It's going straight to voicemail.
语音信箱
Voicemail?
冷静点儿  好吧  数你的钱
Just chill, okay? Count your money.
康宝
Combo,
看见猴子没有
You seen badger?
别帮他打马虎眼
Yo. Don't you cover for him!
我问你问题
I ask you a straight-up question,
你就给我直接答
I expect a straight-up anwser.
怎么
Well?
他们不敢告诉我
They were too scared to tell me.
猴子被抓了
Badger got busted.
他在监狱里
He's in jail.
宝贝儿  我回来啦
Honey, I'm home!
太慢啦  过得怎么样
Too slow! What's up?
你的命比该死的猫还多[猫有九条命]
You've got more lives than a damn cat.
现在我就差学会自己舔毛啦
Now if I can only learn to lick myself.
过得怎么样  伙计们  见到你真好
What's up, guys? Good to see you.
好啦
All right!
回去工作吧  看在上帝份上
Let's all go back to work, for christ's sake!
来我办公室  老弟  让我看看
In my office, man. Let's see what
你们这帮怪物最近在鼓捣啥
You bozos have been up to lately.
你还好吧
You okay?
挺过来了
Hanging in?
你看呢
What's it look like?
警局送来的这是什么东西
What's this from APD?
我跟他们联系过  问他们
I been checking with them to see if they
见没见过那位大名鼎鼎的蓝冰毒贩
come across that famous blue meth of yours.
碰巧的是  昨天晚上
Sure enough, last night.
他们抓了个货真价实的毒贩子
Got themselves an honest-to-God dealer.
我正想开车过去打个招呼
I was thinking of cruising over and saying hello.
也许你想一起去
Maybe you'd like to go with me.
好啊
Well, all right.
你当面告诉我说你不是警察的  伙计
You told me to my face you weren't a cop, man.
我觉得被利用了
I feel manipulated.
我以为我们能一起出去玩
I thought we were gonna hang out.
我们正一起玩呢  猴子
We are hanging out, badger.
你喜欢我叫你猴子还是布兰登
You like Badger or Brandon?
我喜欢  那些  不滥用宪法的人
I like people who don't, like, abuse the constitution.
猴子  听我说
Badger, listen.
兄弟  我这是在帮你
I'm trying to help you here, man.
只要你告诉我谁给你供货
If you just tell me who your supplier is,
我想你就没什么大事了
I think this can end very well for you.
怎么我不在场就跟我的当事人谈话
What are you doing talking to my client without me present?
鬼鬼祟祟的小贱货
You sneaky pete!
什么跟什么呀
Which is which?
怎么  你从娘胎里出来就被警局雇了
What, did the academy hire you right out of the womb?
你们这帮家伙越来越年轻了
You guys get younger every...
你跟娃娃脸说了什么  有没有说傻话
What'd you say to baby-face? Did you say anything stupid?
我说的"傻话"  是指说任何话
By anything stupid, I mean anything at all.
你看你  张着个嘴  像个吱哩哇啦的伴唱
Look at you. Mouth open, vocal chords a-twitter.
我们待会儿再说  现在  你出去
We'll talk about it later. Right now, You out.
10分钟  去吧
Ten minutes ago! Go on!
这是有法律的  探员
There are laws, detective.
你幼儿园老师肯定给你念过吧
Have your kindergarten teacheah, right?
去喝包果汁  睡个午觉  去吧
Go grab a juice box. Have a nap. Go on.
好了
All right.
你是哪位
Who do we have?
布兰登·梅休
Brandon Mayhew.
好
All right.
布兰登·梅休
Brandon Mayhew.
我们开始  公共场所手淫
Here we go. Public masturbation.
-什么  -我不明白  你干嘛那样
- What? - I don't get it. What's the kick?
干嘛不在家干  就跟我们其他人那样
Why don't you do it at home, like the rest of us
对着纯平电视  看着50个台的收费节目
With a big flat-screen TV, 50 channels of pay-per-view?
在星巴克  真不错
In a starbucks. That's nice.
那不是我啊  老兄
That ain't me, man!
我是  我是那个卖冰毒的
I was... I was the guy who was selling meth.
据称是
Allegedly.
好了  明白了  冰毒  对对
All right. I got you. Meth. Right.
抱歉  对错号了
Sorry, that was a little transpositional error.
不是什么大问题
Nothing a little wite-out can't take care of.
够判重罪的量
And a felony quantity.
-刚超过  -是啊  刚超过
- Just barely. - Yeah, just barely.
这的警察都跟卖肉的屠夫一样
The cops around here are like butchers,
都会用指头碰秤杆
Always got their thumbs the scales.
不过庭上争这个就看运气了
But good luck arguing that in court.
我们说正事吧
Let me get down to brass tacks.
我会给你一个打电话的机会
I'm going to get you a second phone call.
你可以打给你妈妈或者爸爸
You're gonna call your mommy or your daddy
或者你的教区牧师  童子军队长
Or your parish priest or your boy scout leader,
让他们给我张四千六百五十块的支票
And they're going to deliver me a check for $4,650.
我会把数字写在名片后面
I'll write that down on the back of my business card.
四  六  五  零
4-6-5-0.
我要现金支票
And I need that in a cashier's check
汇票也行  都不要紧
Or a money order, doesn't matter.
事实上  我想要汇票
Actually, I want it in a money order.
收款写冰站斑马联盟
And make it out to ice station zebra associates.
那是我的户头  完全合法
That's my loan-out. It's totally legit.
只是为了避税的缘故
It's done just for tax purposes.
之后我们可以讨论用维萨还是万事达
After that, we can discuss Visa or Mastercard,
美国运通绝对不行  你也别问了
But definitely not American express, so don't even ask.
还有问题吗
Any questions?
你会帮我脱罪的  是吧
You're gonna get me off, right?
怎么  我看起来很像你高中女朋友吗
What, do I look like your high school girlfriend?
摸上几下就等不及了
Five fingers no waiting?
我说笑话呢  布兰登
That's a joke, Brandon.
笑一笑
Lighten up.
孩子  我向你保证
Son, I promise you this.
我会给你钱能买到的
I will give you the best criminal
最好的刑事辩护
defense that money can buy?
弗朗西斯卡  我已经搞定了
Francesca, I took these already.
我不是都搞定了吗
Didn't I take these already?
听着  那是你的问题
Look, it's on your head. You're not
你不应该吃双倍的维他命A
supposed to double Vitamin A,
对肝脏不好
It's bad for the liver.
好了  下一个是谁
Okay, who's next?
见过了  我见过他了
Did him. I did him.
他选了公共辩护律师  谢谢你了
That one went public defender. Thanks for nothing.
我那个手淫的小朋友呢
What happened to my masturbator friend
你搞得我晕头转向的
You get me turn around
别挂电话  我待会儿跟你说
Hang on. I'll get back to you.
先生们  我察觉到你们在谈论我的代理人
Gentlemen, I sense you're discussing my client.
有什么能跟我分享的吗
Anything you care to share with me?
当然  你的那些广告烂透了
Sure. Your commercials? They suck ass.
我在抽风的妓院里看的戏都比这好
I've seen better acting in an epileptic whorehouse.
是你妈工作的那家妓院吗
Is that like the one your mom works at?
她还搞买一赠一优惠吗
Is she still offering the two-for-one discount?
禁毒署哈
DEA, huh?
当街抓人
For a street bust.
两家衙门想拿那小讨厌鬼怎么样呢
Now, what would two feds want with that little twerp?
这种事早晚都会有的
Sooner or later, this was gonna happen.
你想要指数增长
You want your exponential growth,
准会有人被抓  就这么简单
Guys are gonna get busted. Simple as that.
我们给他请个真正的律师如何
So how about we get him a real attorney?
我是说  这是什么鬼东西
I mean, what the hell is this?
这就是他雇的人
This is who he hires?
什么  开什么玩笑
What? Are you kidding me?
这是最佳人选  如果是我就会请他
This is the guy you want. This is the guy I'd hire.
-这就是你要请的人  -还记得埃米利奥吗
- It's the guy you'd hire. - Look, you remember Emilio?
这家伙把埃米利奥弄出来两次了
This dude got Emilio off, like, twice.
每次都差点判死刑了
Both times, they had him dead to rights, yo.
却又逃了出来
And then poof!
那家伙像是霍迪尼
Dude's like Houdini.
Houdini: 魔术界逃脱大师
说实话  事情变棘手了
Seriously, when the going gets tough,
该找个刑事律师了
You don't want a criminal lawyer.
你要找"刑事案"律师
You want a "criminal" lawyer.
懂我的意思吗
Know what I'm saying?
看  我们都没事  怀特先生
Look, we're in good shape, Mr. White.
猴子对我们忠心耿耿
Badger's way too loyal to roll.
而且他还很怕我
Plus he's scared shitless of me.
我们出了四千美元  是做生意成本费
We pay four large. Cost of business.
从猴子的工资里扣
Take it out of Badger
这是他第一次失手  会差到哪里去呢
And it's only his first dealing rap, so worst case scenario?
他们把他保释出来
They plead him out, he does five months
他捡了五个月的垃圾
picking up litter ina fellow potato-eate
谁在里面接应
So who goes inside?
我不想露面
I don't need them seeing my face.
我不想让他们看到我
为什么  你一看就是常客
Why not? You look like his typical clientele.
扯蛋
Dick.
好
Fine.
我们抛硬币
We'll flip for it.
选一个
Call it.
人头
Heads.
梅休  梅休先生
Mayhew? Mr. Mayhew?
梅休先生
Mr. Mayhew.
欢迎光临  请坐
Nice of you to come down. please.
看看
Look at you.
我该报警说我找到D.B.库帕了吗
Should I call the FBI and tell them I found D.B.Cooper?
D.B.Cooper: 越狱里的人物
开玩笑
Joking.
过来
Please, come on.
过来吧
Come on.
请过来
Please.
你好
Hello.
索尔·古德曼
Saul Goodman.
请坐
Please sit.
很抱歉  我们要这么
So it's a shame that we have to
偷偷摸摸的见面
Meet under theseme mystery
你应该有什么东西要给我吧
I believe you have something for me?
梅休  是爱尔兰人还是英国人
Mayhew. Is that irish or english?
爱尔兰人
Irish.
天哪  爱吃土豆的同性恋
Faith and begorrah! A fellow potato-eater.
我的真名叫麦吉尔
My real name's Mcgill.
起个犹太名是为了吸引老乡
The jew thing I just do for the homeboys.
可以说  他们只要同乡人
They all want a pipe-hitting
为他们脱罪
member of the tribe, so to speak
我跑题了  有好事发生
I digress. Good things are happening.
你的侄子马上就出来了
Fact is, your nephew's gonna get out in no time.
太好了
That's wonderful.
还有些细节问题要解决
There's still a few details to be ironed out,
但现在缉毒局牵扯进来了
But now that the DEA is involved,
我看他多半是要判刑或者缓刑
I think he's looking at time served and probation.
把你的电话给弗朗西斯卡  我们稍后联系
So leave your number with francesca, and we'll be in touch.
抱歉  缉毒局
Excuse me, the DEA?
毒品缉私局
That's the drug enforcement administration.
联邦调查局人员
The feds.
我不想说破的
I hope that I'm not the breaker of bad news,
但你的侄子
But your nephew got mixed up with
和一些来路不明的人搅在一起
Some pretty nasty customers
我明白
I understand that. But what does
但这和缉毒局有什么关系
That have to do with the DEA
他们在跟踪一个神秘人物
They're after some mystery man,
叫做海森堡的重量级神秘人物
Some heavy-hitter that goes by the name Heisenberg.
他们迫切想找到此人  就像刀想切肉
They want this guy like the ax wants the turkey.
貌似小布兰登能提供信息
Seems young Brandon may have information
找到海森堡
that could lead Heisenberg...
开心点
Jesus, cheer up!
这是好消息
This is good news. I mean,
布兰登首先冲进粪堆
Brandon fell head-first into the doo-doo pile
他得沾上点古龙水的味道才能出来
And came up smelling like Paco Rabanne.
听着
Look, look.
我觉得  我们应该
I just think that we should
看看有什么其他选择
Review our options.
选择
Options?
我来告诉你  你有什么选择
I'm gonna tell you what your options are.
你一共有两个选择
And you got a grand total of two.
第一  布兰登老实做事
Option a, Brandon takes the deal.
第二  布兰登进监狱
Option b, Brandon goes up to the penitentiary
尝尝被人爆菊花的滋味
And gets his rectum resized about yay big.
听着  会不会
Look, look. what about...
遭人报复  如果猴子
Reprisals? I mean, if badger...
如果布兰登
If Brandon...
把海森堡供出来
Informs on this Heisenberg...
要是  希望不会
I mean, what if... god forbid...
他们会不会
That they decide to...
报复
Take revenge?
你怎么跟他说的
What have you been telling him?
那孩子一直在叫
The kid keeps spouting off about
"如果我说了  他们会要了我的命"
"if i talk, thehat's not good
现在他可是这案子的关键
Right now, he's the only thing holding up this deal.
-很好  -一点都不好
- Good. - No, that's not good.
太恐怖了  相信我  先生
That's terrible. Trust me, sir,
你的侄子在监狱里呆不了两星期的
Your nephew won't last in prison two weeks.
你得劝他冒一次险
You let him take his chances on the outside.
或许我该申请证人保护
Maybe I can work in some witness protection.
不  听我说
No, look, look.
那是一群穷凶极恶的人
These are vicious, desperate people.
我听说
I've been told that
他们有人杀了人
One of them killed another man
用ATM机碾碎了他的脑袋
By crushing his head with an ATM machine.
人们总喜欢从ATM机中找点乐子
People love to take credit for the fun ones.
被爆头的那个家伙
The guy who got his head smooshed
曾经是我的客户  他说
Used to be a cged," he said.
他的妻子杀了他  对吧  这是众所周知的
His wife killed him, all right? It was open and shut.
相信我  你们没啥好担心的
Trust me, you folks have nothing to worry about, okay?
我会把你侄子弄出来的
I'm gonna set your nephew straight,
保证安然无恙
Get him singing like a canary...
一切都会好的
All's right with the world.
1万美元
$10,000.
1万
10,000.
现金付款
Cash to you.
我没说让你不管案子
I'm not saying to throw the case.
别告诉缉毒局
No talking to the DEA.
你说的是我心里想的话吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
是的
Yes.
会怎么样
What's it going to be?
那家伙不肯被收买
That dude wouldn't take a bribe?
那家伙在那里  是我们口中的索尔·古德曼吗
That dude in there? Saul Goodman we're talking about?
"引起道德公愤"  他说
"Morally outraged," he said.
-威胁我说要报警  -猴子要告密
- Threatened to call the police. - And badger's gonna spill?
像埃克森·瓦尔迪兹号邮轮泄油事件一样
Like the Exxon Valdez.
我们该怎么做
So what do we do about it?
弗朗西斯卡  我跟着你回家怎么样
Francesca, how about I follow you home?
不用
No.
确保你安全
For safety!
天哪  你差点要了我的命
God, you are killing me with that booty.
别这样  伙计们
Talk to me, guys!
别这样  告诉我你们想要怎么样  天哪
Come on. Just tell me what you want! Jesus!
不  不  不 ...
Oh, No no...
不是我  是伊格纳西奥  是他
It wasn't me! It was Ignacio! He's the one!
闭嘴
Shut up!
好吧  说英语
All right, just speak english.
不是拉罗派你们来的吗  不是拉罗
Lalo didn't send you? No Lalo?
-是谁  -谢天谢地
- Who? - Thank god!
我以为
I thought...
先生们  我能为你做些什么
What can I do for you, gentlemen?
任何事  告诉我你需要什么
Anything! Just tell me what you need.
今天下午  我们的同事给你1万美元
This afternoon, an associate of ours offered you $10,000.
你应该接受那笔钱的
You should have taken it!
等等  这是为了感谢我告诉你们他的名字
Wait a minute. This is in regards to what's-his-name?
猴子  布兰登·梅休
Badger! Brandon Mayhew.
他叔叔  是你们的人
The uncle. That was your guy?
无意冒犯  伙计
No offense, guys, but I don't take
我不接受陌生人的行贿
Bribes from strangers, you know?
力求稳妥  那是我的座右铭
Better safe than sorry. That's my motto.
但你的钱我会收的  我保证
But I'll take your money! Sure!
过期无效
That offer's expired, yo.
开价有点低  但还过得去  我接受了
It was kind of low anyways. But okay, okay, I'll take it.
告诉我  你想要什么
Just tell me what you need.
我好说  我会保持乐观的心态
I'm easy. I'm going to keep a happy thought
并且假定这只是一个谈判策略
And assume this is just a negotiating tactic.
好吧  仔细听我说
All right, listen to me very carefully.
你要给猴子·梅休
You are going to give Badger Mayhew the best
最好的合法辩护
Legal representation ever.
别牵扯到缉毒局
But no deals with the DEA!
好吗  猴子不会指证任何人的
All right? badger will not identify anyone to anybody.
如果他指证  你就死定了
If he does, you're dead!
你为什么不杀了猴子
Why don't you just kill badger?
听我说  伙计们  如果一只蚊子在你旁边嗡嗡叫
Follow me, guys, but if a mosquito's buzzing around you,
咬了你的屁股
It bites you on the ass, you don't go
你不会去找蚊子的律师算账吧
gunning for the mosquito's attorney.
你会去拿苍蝇拍  可以这样比喻
You go grab a flyswatter. I mean, so to speak.
冒昧的说
I mean, all due respect, do I
这点还需要我为您说明吗
have to spell this out for you?
我们不会杀了猴子的
We're not killing badger, yo!
那你真正的麻烦才出现
Then you got real problems.
缉毒局会像你对我一样
'Cause the DEA is gonna come down
对你的小弟施以严刑
On your boy like a proverbial ton of bricks.
我不觉得自己能活着回去
I don't think I'm going out on a limb here,
但他也不会顶罪入狱
but he's not gonna like prison.
不管你怎么对我
He's gonna sing like Ceine Dion
他会招供的
Regardless of what you do to me.
梅休先生
Mr. Mayhew?
我记得你的咳嗽
I recognize your cough.
脱下面具吧  呼吸点新鲜空气
Take that mask off. Get some air.
继续
Go on.
放松点  吸气  呼气
Take it easy! Breathe in, breathe out.
我想站起来  行吗  我的膝盖有毛病
I'm gonna stand up, all right? 'Cause I got bad knees.
好些了
That's better.
听着  我们三个人准备把这事搞定
Now listen. The three of us are gonna work this out.
怎么搞
How?
首先
First things first, you're gonna put
你们每人在我口袋里放一美元
A dollar in my pocket, both of you.
你想要律师委托人保密特权吗
You want attorney-client privilege?
这样才能确保天知地知你知我知
So that everything you say is strictly between us.
我是认真的
I mean it!
在我口袋里放一美元  拜托  正式一点
Put a dollar in my pocket. Come on, make it official.
快啊  动手
Come on, do it!
这就对了  就只是一美元嘛
That's it. Come on. just a dollar.
好了  轮到你了  滑雪迷  来吧
All right, now you, ski bum. come on.
给一美元吧
Give with the dollar.
-快啊  -放聪明点
- Go on. - Be smart.
怎么
What?
-我只有一张5块的  -5块也行啊
- All I got's a 5.  - I'll take a 5!
来吧  来吧
Come on, already. come on.
这就对了嘛
Be cool.
你们现在已经正式
You're now both officially represented
授予索尔·古德曼及他的事务所代理
by Sole Goodman and associates.
即使砸掉我律师的饭碗  我也绝对保守秘密
Your secrets are safe with me under threat of disbarment.
把那个滑雪面具摘下来吧  我感觉像是
Take the ski mask off. I feel like I'm
在跟地下气象台的人说话一样
talking to a Weather Underground here.
摘下来吧
Do it.
所以监狱暴动免谈
So if a prison shanking is completely off the table...
这点都同意吧
And we're sure of that?
绝不暴动
No shanking!
好吧  好吧
All right all right.
那么在我看来
Then the way I see it is...
总得有人坐牢
Somebody's going to prison.
关键就在于是谁
It's just a matter of who.
好了
All right.
虽然广告上驴劲十足
Lame-ass TV ads aside,
当了你的律师  为你编了一套不错的托词
Your lawyer here, he cooked you up a pretty killer deal.
羁押候审  无缓刑  他还挺伶牙俐齿的
Time served, no probation. He's pretty slick.
真不敢相信法官就这样同意了
Couldn't believe the judge went for it.
先别得意  你还没自由呢
Don't get cocky. You ain't home free yet.
你不交待供货商的名字
You don't give us the name of your
就不保证你会得到什么样的宣判了
supplier, I don't know what you'll stand up to, I guess.
探员  没必要鲁莽行事
Agent, the tough guy act is unnecessary.
这位年轻人还是很配合我们工作的
This young man is cooperating fully.
是吗  你很配合我们工作吗
Is that right?  You cooperating?
好吧
OK
那先从名字开始吧
Let's start with a name.
我只知道他叫海森堡
He just goes by Heisenberg.
海森堡
Heisenberg.
这位海森堡多大年纪
How old's this Heisenberg?
比较老
Old.
50或者70左右的样子吧
Like 50 or 70 or something.
-身高  -大概中等身材
- Height?  - Average, I guess.
中等个头  中等体型
Medium height, medium weight.
头发什么颜色
What color hair?
光头
No hair.
头比你还光
Dude's balder than you.
1963年
1963.
詹姆斯·爱德华·柯凯力因偷窃自动贩卖机
James Edward Kilkelly is convicted
而被起诉
of stealing a vending machine.
1975年  入室抢劫
1975. Breaking and entering.
1982年  盗车
1982. Grand theft auto.
1984年  持枪抢劫
1984. Armed robbery.
1987年  1992年  你们知道
1987. 1992. You get the idea.
这是他现在的样子
And here he is today.
以"来去自如的吉米"著称
Better known today as Jimmy In-'n-out.
在城里  国家以至联邦各种监狱呆过
City, state, federal
58年的刑期  他在里面呆了44年
He's spent 44 of the last 58 years inside.
在牢狱里度过一生
An entire life behind bars.
吉米提供一项很特别的服务
Jimmy provides a very special service.
给一笔钱  他可以为你进监狱
For a price, Jimmy will go to prison for you.
故意
On purpose?
这家伙故意进监狱
The guy goes to prison on purpose?
他在里面觉得更舒服
He's actually more comfortable inside.
外面的世界对他来说太残酷了
The outside world hasn't been too kind to him.
克林顿执政的时期
Sometime during the Clinton administration,
吉米还想出了怎样
Jimmy figured out how he could use
靠他的小聪明挣钱
his talents to turn a profit.
-什么时候可以开始  -已经开始了
- When does all this happen? - It's already happening.
交易明天进行
The buy is set for tomorrow.
警察搞定吉米  猴子趁机逃走  皆大欢喜
Cops bust Jimmy, Badger gets out, everybody's happy,
所有这些要花你八万美元
And all it's gonna cost you is 80,000
外加一磅上等冰毒
And one pound of your finest meth.
八万块抵他八年的牢狱生涯  是吗
$80,000 for eight years of his life, huh?
首先一点  他不会被判8年的
First of all, he's not gonna do eight years.
由我代表他  并且我保证
I'm gonna represent him, and I guarantee
在诉讼过程中
There's gonna be some unexpected
会有一些预料不到的问题
Problems with the the prosecution's case.
其次  他拿三万  我拿五万
Secondly, he gets 30. 50 goes to me.
-你拿五万  凭什么  -凭我协助了你们
- You get 50?  For what?  - For facilitating.
谁担的风险更大呢  他喜欢监狱
Who's taking a bigger risk?  He likes prison.
你们带了现金对吗
You did bring the cash, didn't you?
听着  要是这个选择太昂贵
Look, if this option is too expensive,
你们还可以  猴子在监狱餐厅呢
You can still always... Badger in the chow line.
良心也贵啊  不是吗
Conscience gets expensive, doesn't it?
好了  目标出现了
All right. There's our boy.
很准时
Right on time.
-往回走  -什么  好吧
- Go back. - What?  All right.
那么
So...
你怎么看  他们发现我们了吗
What do you think? Did they see us?
我觉得我们没事
I think we're good.
猴子看起来想要吐的样子
Badger looks like he's gonna throw up.
拿给我  快给我
Give me those back. Just give them to me!
见鬼  吉米在哪儿  十分钟之前
Where the hell is jimmy?  He should
他就应该在这儿了
have been here ten minutes ago.
你相信吉米这个人是真的么
You think Jimmy's actually for real?
一个想进监狱的人
A guy who wants what's to be in prison.
监狱可不止一种含义
There's more than one kind of prison.
那是什么意思
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
等等
Wait a minute.
不 不 不
No no no...
什么什么  让我看看
What? What? Let me see.
-那他妈是谁  -不知道
- Who the hell is that?  - I don't know.
我猜  是海森堡先生吧
Mr. Heisenberg, I presume.
该行动了吗
Time to move?
等他们交易
Not till we see the exchange.
不 不 不  残了
NO no no  oh shit
-怎么  -现在才是他
- What?  - Now he shows.
可以开始了吗
Okay, let's do this.
我的天  吉米坐错地方了
My god. Jimmy's on the wrong bench. crap!
我们惨了
We are screwed!
你干什么
What are you doing?
搞不懂  怎么磨磨蹭蹭的
I don't get it. What's the holdup?
东西呢  老兄
Where's the stuff, man?
-往哪走啊  -给我闭嘴
- Where are we going? - Just shut up.
-下车  拦住他  -缉毒局的人就在那儿呢
- Get out. Go stop him. - The DEA is right there.
要是他们发现我  我们就完了
If they see me, we're screwed.
下车  我会处理的
Get out. I'll do something!
-什么  -快下车
- What?  - Go!
汉克  原来是你啊
Hank, I thought that was you!
施拉德  视线受阻
Schrader, I'm blocked.
-我现在很忙  -你近来怎么样  感觉还好吗
- Not a good time. - How you doing? Are you feeling okay?
施拉德  视线受阻
Schrader, I'm blocked.
我们在工作  你赶紧把车开走
We're working. You gotta get out of here.
你们在工作  是缉毒局的那些工作吗
You're working?  like DEA working?
出了什么大事吗
Is something going down?
认错人了  认错人了  在另一个椅子上
Wrong guy! Wrong guy! other bench.
沃尔特 沃尔特 ...
Walt Walt ...
-快走开啦  -行行  我这就走
- Move your ass now!  - Okay. I'll go and leave you alone.
-等会儿再聊吧  -往前开  往前开
- We'll talk about it later. - Just forward! forward!
往前开吗  那我走了
Forward is better?  I'll be out of the way then?
抱歉  行了吧  抱歉
I'm sorry. All right?  I'm sorry.
-你们忙吧  -待会儿再聊  快走吧
- I'll leave you alone. - We'll talk later. Just go.
他去哪儿了  他妈的到哪儿去了
Where'd he go?  Where the hell'd he go?
等等
Wait.
发现他了
Got him.
-看来有情况  -把他们拿下
- Looks like it's going down. - Take them!
不准动  就那  别动
Freeze. Right there. Don't move.
天啊
Jesus.
他们好像买账了
I think they bought it.
当然了
Absolutely.
顺利逮获  长官
Textbook bust, sir.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我们截获了一整磅的冰毒
Looks like we got a full pound of the blue stuff.
海森堡的真名吗
And Heisenberg's real name?
詹姆斯·柯凯力
James Kilkelly.
非常感谢  我的荣幸
Thank you very much. It was my pleasure.
你不在家
You weren't home,
所以我让搬运队进来了  希望这无大碍
So I let the delivery guys in. I hope that's okay.
当然
Absolutely.
你买了张床
So you bought a bed.
什么尺寸  大号的
What is that? A king?
带枕头
Pillow top?
天哪
My god.
你还真是化学老师
You really are a chemistry teacher.
不介意吧
You mind?
我化学学得很烂
I was terrible at chemistry.
我更偏向于人文学科
I'm more of a humanities guy.
-你怎么找到我的  -我们应该谈谈那件事
- How did you find me?  - We should talk about that.
要找到你可不是一般的难啊
It should be much, much harder for people to track you down.
我的私人调查员收了我三个小时的费用
My P.I. charged me for three hours.
我很怀疑他有没有用到一个小时
So I seriously doubt it took him more than one.
那么这就是所谓的
So this is what,
要挟吗
Blackmail?
我是你的律师
I'm your lawyer.
你对我说的一切都是保密的
Anything you say to me is totally privileged.
我又不是那种搞敲诈勒索的人
I'm not in the shake-down racket.
我是律师
I'm a lawyer.
甚至毒品贩子都是需要律师的  对吗
Even drug dealers need lawyers, right?
尤其是毒品贩子
Especially drug dealers.
那又怎样  你这样做
So what, you're just doing this out
就是出于你自己的好心
of the kindness of your heart?
拜托  你知道我的每小时工资多少吗
Come on. Have you seen my hourly rate?
顺便问下  你把钱放哪儿
By the way, where do you keep the money?
是放在床垫里吗  或者是
Is it in your mattress? Is it in a
放在果冻盒子里埋在后院吗
jelly jar, buried inside your yard huh?
你的搭档小鬼说不定是
This kid mayhew may be the first
第一个被抓的
of your guys get picked up.
但他不会是最后一个  要是我能找到你
But he won't be the last. And if I can find you,
那么离警察盯上你又有多远呢
How far behind can the cops be?
我搞不懂
I don't understand.
你到底想干什么
What exactly are you offering to do for me?
汤姆·海根对维托·克里昂做了什么  [《教父》角色]
What did Tom Hagen do for Vito Corleone?
我又不是维托·克里昂
I'm no Vito Corleone.
别开玩笑了  现在你就是弗利多  [《教父》角色]
No shit!  Right now, you're Fredo.
但是有合理的建议
But with some sound advice and the
和适当的引导  谁会晓得呢
proper introductions who knows?
我告诉你一点  你的产品不错
I'll tell you one thing, you've got the right product.
要是被缉毒局盯上了的
Anything that gets the DEA's panties in this big a bunch...
就吃不了兜着走了
You're on to something special.
我愿意为此尽点薄力
And I would like to be a small and silent part of it.
好好考虑下吧
Food for thought, yeah?
假如你想多赚些钱
So if you want to make more money
并且想把赚来的钱留住
And keep the money that you make...
"请致电索尔"
"Better Call Saul!"